Guide to the Office of the President, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
President's office, Yale University, records
1718-2002
RU 834
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
8.5
(9 boxes, 1 folio)
The records consist of correspondence, a notebook, and subject files documenting activities of academic units, development and alumni affairs, finance, legal affairs, and agencies and organizations affiliated with Yale University. The records span the administrations of several presidents of Yale University.
Yale University. President's Office
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 2-A (YRG 2-A), Records of the Yale president's office.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the materials is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, a notebook, and subject files documenting activities of academic units, development and alumni affairs, finance, legal affairs, and agencies and organizations affiliated with Yale University. The records span the administrations of several presidents of Yale University.
Universities and colleges -- Administration; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Presidents; Yale University. President's Office
- Letter to Samual Andrew from T. Woodbridge [photostat], 1718; Accession 1979-A-029
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - Letter to Samual Andrew from T. Woodbridge [photostat], 1718 (Box 1)
- Naphtali Daggett, Chapter from the Laws of Yale College, circa 1770; Accession 1979-A-030
  - Naphtali Daggett, Chapter from the Laws of Yale College, circa 1770 (Box 1)
- Petition from Noah Porter and Yale College faculty to President Rutherford B. Hayes regarding Chinese immigration, 1879; Accession 1985-A-048; 2.5; (1 folio) (Box AF7)
- Records of the president, 1973-1992; Accession 2000-A-020
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2027
  - ACADEMIC UNITS
    - 1991-1992
      - Center for International and Area Studies (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Luce Center for International and Area Studies (general) (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Forestry and Environmental Studies, School of - Deanship Search (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Operations Research (general) (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1990-1991
      - Center for International and Area Studies (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Luce Center for International and Area Studies (general) (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Drama School Deanship Search Candidates (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Forestry and Environmental Studies, School of, Deanship Search (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Law School (general) (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Nursing, School of - Agreement with Yale-New Haven Hospital, 1990 November 29 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Committee on the Yale School of Nursing--Committee Interview Notes (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - Draft Report of the Committee on the Yale School Of Nursing (Ruddle Committee), 1991 June 7 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - "Public" Version of Ruddle Committee Report (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - Report of the Committee on the Yale School Of Nursing (Ruddle Committee) (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - 1989-1990
      - Center for International and Area Studies (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Global Change at Yale, Center for the Study of (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Nursing, School of (general) (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Operations Research (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - 1988-1989
      - Epidemiology and Public Health (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - Law School Renovations (Box 1, Folder 29 - 30)
      - Nursing, School of (general) (Box 1, Folder 31)
        - Report of Self-Study/Programs of Study (Box 2, Folder 32)
      - Operations Research (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - 1987-1988
      - Afro and Afro-American Studies (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - Law School (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - Nursing, School of (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - 1986-1987
      - Comparative Literature (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - Law School (Box 2, Folder 38)
      - Lesbian and Gay Studies (Box 2, Folder 39)
      - Organization and Management, School of (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - 1984-1985
      - Law School (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - VICE PRESIDENT FOR DEVELOPMENT AND ALUMNI AFFAIRS
    - 1991-1992
      - Campaign -General (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - 1990-1991
      - Campaign -General (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - 1989-1990
      - Campaign -General (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - 1988-1989
      - Campaign -General (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - 1987-1988
  - VICE PRESIDENT FOR FINANCE AND ADMINISTRATION
    - 1991-1992
      - Finance (Box 2, Folder 49)
        - Capital Budget, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 50)
        - Capital Budget, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 51)
        - The Financial Situation of the University (Box 2, Folder 52)
        - Long-term Financial Planning/10 Year Academic Plan (Box 2, Folder 53 - 54)
        - Long-Range Plan/10 Year Budget (Box 2, Folder 55 - 56)
    - 1990-1991
      - Finance, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 57)
        - Budgets -General (Box 3, Folder 58)
        - Endowment (Box 3, Folder 59)
        - Long-Range Academic Plan (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - 1988-1989
      - Long-Range Academic Plan (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - 1987-1988
      - Labor Relations (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - 1986-1987
      - Vice President for Finance (Box 3, Folder 63)
      - Five-Year Plan (budgets) (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - GENERAL COUNSEL
    - Tax Exemption (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - PRESIDENT
    - 1991-1992
      - Free Speech (Box 3, Folder 66)
      - Officers Meetings (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - 1990-1991
      - Free Speech (Box 3, Folder 68)
      - Officers Meetings (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - 1989-1990
      - Officers Meetings (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - 1988-1989
      - Free Speech (Box 3, Folder 71)
      - Officers Meetings (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - 1986-1987
      - Free Speech (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - 1987-1988
      - Free Speech (Box 3, Folder 74)
      - Officers Meetings (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - 1986-1987
      - Congratulatory Letters-Schmidt (Bart Giamatti to Benno Schmidt) (Box 3, Folder 76)
      - Article: A. Whitney Griswold by K. Brewster, Jr. (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - 1985-1986
      - Free Speech (Box 3, Folder 78)
      - Photographs (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - 1983-1984
      - Free Speech (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - 1977-78
      - President, Office of (Photograph of Hanna Gray) (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - 1973-74
      - Free Speech (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - SECRETARY
    - 1991-1992
      - Campus Police (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - AFFILIATED ORGANIZATIONS
    - 1991-1992
      - Yale-New Haven Hospital (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - 1990-1991
      - Press, Yale (Box 3, Folder 86)
      - Review, Yale (Box 3, Folder 87 - 88)
      - Whitney Humanities Center Directorship Search (D. Bromwich) (Box 3, Folder 89)
      - Yale-New Haven Hospital - Campaign (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - 1989-1990
      - Press, Yale (Box 3, Folder 91)
      - Review, Yale (Box 3, Folder 92)
      - Yale-New Haven Hospital - Campaign (Box 3, Folder 93)
      - Yale-New Haven Medical Center, Inc. (Box 3, Folder 94)
    - 1988-1989
      - Yale-New Haven Hospital (Box 3, Folder 95)
      - Yale-New Haven Hospital - Campaign (Box 3, Folder 96)
    - 1987-1988
      - Whitney Humanities Center (Box 3, Folder 97)
      - Yale-New Haven Medical Center, Inc. (Box 3, Folder 98)
      - Yale-New Haven Teachers Institute (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - ANNUAL REPORTS
    - 1986-1987
      - Afro and Afro-American Studies (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - ART GALLERY, LIBRARIES, MUSEUMS, PAPERS
    - 1988-1989
      - Art Gallery (Box 3, Folder 101)
      - Serra Sculpture (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - 1989-1990
      - Library, University (Box 3, Folder 103)
      - Serra Sculpture (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - ATHLETICS
    - 1989-1990
      - Golf Course (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - COMMITTEES
    - 1991-1992
      - Arts Area Advisory Committee (Box 4, Folder 106)
      - Restructuring the Faculty of Arts and Sciences, Committee on (Box 4, Folder 107)
    - 1990-1991
      - Restructuring the Faculty of Arts and Sciences, Committee on (Box 4, Folder 108)
      - Social Thought and Ethics Committee (Box 4, Folder 109)
      - York Street/Chapel Street Site Planning Committee (Box 4, Folder 110)
    - 1989-1990
      - York Street/Chapel Street Site Planning Committee (Box 4, Folder 111)
    - 1988-1989
      - Social Thought and Ethics Committee (Box 4, Folder 112 - 113)
    - 1986-1987
      - Social Thought and Ethics Committee (Box 4, Folder 114)
  - GOVERNMENT (Federal, State, City)
    - Federal (Box 4, Folder 115)
      - 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 116)
        - George Bush -General, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 117)
    - State (Box 4, Folder 118)
      - 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 119)
        - Connecticut Mental Health Center, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 120)
        - Connecticut State Medical Society, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 121)
    - Local (Box 4, Folder 122)
      - 1990-1991
        - Science Park (Box 4, Folder 123)
        - Theoretical and Applied Neuroscience, Center for (Box 4, Folder 124)
      - 1988-1989
        - New Haven, City of (Box 4, Folder 125)
  - TRIPS, PRESIDENT'S
    - Far East Trip, 1991 June (Box 4, Folder 126)
  - OTHER UNIVERSITIES (Box 4, Folder 127)
    - 1991-1992
      - Seoul National University, 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 128)
      - Chinese University of Hong Kong Ceremony, 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 129)
    - 1989-1990
      - President, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 130)
      - Photographs, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 131)
    - 1988-1989
      - Committees, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 132)
      - York Street/Chapel Street Site, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 133)
      - Planning Committee, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 134)
- C-mail sent to Presidents Griswold and Brewster, 1954-1969; Accession 2002-A-080
  - C-mail sent to Presidents Griswold and Brewster, 1954-1969 (Box 1)
- "Yale Blue" notebook, 1911-2002; Accession 2013-A-071 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  "Yale Blue" notebook contains correspondence, swatches, and a history of the development of the particular shade of blue used by Yale University.